<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An order and declaration of the Commons assembled in Parliament: that no person vvithin the city of London, and liberties thereof, shall bee of the Common Councell, or in any office of trust, with in the said city, or have any voyce in the choyce of the same, that hath not voluntarily contributed upon the propositions, according to the ordinance of the 29 of Novemb. 1642. Or, whose persons hath been imprisoned, or estates sequestred for their malignancy, nor taken the late solemn league and covenant. Die Jovis, 19. Decemb. 1644. H. Elsynge Cler. Parl. D. Com.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Parliament. House of Commons.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A83752</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99859646</idno>
  <idno type="VID">111741</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248510855</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing E2631</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E21_28</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R14351</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99859646</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99859646e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A83752)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 111741)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 4:E21[28])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An order and declaration of the Commons assembled in Parliament: that no person vvithin the city of London, and liberties thereof, shall bee of the Common Councell, or in any office of trust, with in the said city, or have any voyce in the choyce of the same, that hath not voluntarily contributed upon the propositions, according to the ordinance of the 29 of Novemb. 1642. Or, whose persons hath been imprisoned, or estates sequestred for their malignancy, nor taken the late solemn league and covenant. Die Jovis, 19. Decemb. 1644. H. Elsynge Cler. Parl. D. Com.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament. House of Commons.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>by Richard Cotes,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Printed at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1644.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">City of London (England). --  Court of Common Council --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Pas </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:111741:1"/>
            <p> AN ORDER AND DECLARATION OF THE COMMONS assembled in PARLIAMENT: That no Person vvithin the City of <hi>London,</hi> and Liberties therof, shall bee of the Common Councell, or in any Office of Trust, within the said City, or have any voyce in the choyce of the same, that hath not voluntarily contributed upon the Propositions, according to the Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance of the 29 of <hi>Novemb.</hi> 1642.</p>
            <p>Or, whose Persons hath been imprisoned, or E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>states Sequestred for their Malignancy, nor taken the late Solemn League and Covenant.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license">
                        <p> </p>
                        <closer>
                           <dateline>
                              <date>
                                 <hi>Die Jovis,</hi> 19. <hi>Decemb.</hi> 1644.</date>
                           </dateline>
                           <signed>H. Elsynge Cler. Parl. D. Com.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>Printed at <hi>London</hi> by <hi>Richard Cotes.</hi> 1644.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:111741:2"/>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:111741:2"/>
            <head>AN ORDER AND DECLARATION OF THE COMMONS ASSEMBLED IN PARLIAMENT.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>HE Commons ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king into their consi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration, that the well governing and peace of the Citie of London and the Liberties thereof,
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:111741:3"/> doth chiefely depend upon the faithfulnesse and integritie of the persons that have and beare the publique Offices and Places of Trust therein; And that in these times of trouble, more then ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary care is to bee taken in the choyce and election of them, and that their good Affection to the true Protestant Religion and to the Parliament and peace of the Citie and Kingdome, should bee openly testified and made knowne before they bee admitted to any such Place or Office. And whereas by the ancient Customes and Vsa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges of the said Citie, those of the Common-Councell, and some o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Officers of the Citie, are to
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:111741:3"/> bee chosen at or about the one and twentieth day of this instant <hi>December.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Commons doe Order and Declare, that no person shall bee elected into any the said Offices, nor shall bee capable thereof, who have not voluntarily contributed upon the Propositions, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Ordinance of the nine and twentieth of <hi>November,</hi> 1642. Or who have otherwise testified their disaffection to the Parliament, or who have not ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken the late solemne League and Covenant; And further that no person shall have any voyce in such Election, whose Person hath been Imprisoned or Estate Sequestred
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:111741:4"/> for Malignancie against the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, or that hath not taken the said Solemne League and Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant. And <hi>Thomas Atkin</hi> Lord Major of the Citie of London, and the Aldermen in their severall Wards, and all other Persons to whom the Election of any the said Officers shall appertaine, are here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by required to see this Order due<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly put in Execution.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>H. Elsynge Cler. Parl. D. Com.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:111741:4"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>